# **Kusum Thapa**

Colchester, Essex, kusumthapa\_magar@hotmail.com, 07575813945

https://kusum-thapa.github.io/

## **Profile**

Highly motivated, enthusiastic and hardworking software developer with more than 3 years of experience on MIS software development field. Technically proficient with sound knowledge of software technologies especially in ASP.net programming and data management. Good interpersonal skills and a great team attitude with an ability to deal with all clients at all levels of the business. Acquire a valid DBS clearance certificate. Took a career break to start family abroad and worked in various other roles that fit around personal commitment and further enhanced my personal skills. Upon deciding to return back and rebuild career in technology currently looking to secure a software developer role with an established company where I can utilise and further develop my skills and aid company growth.

## **Key Skills and Achievements**

#### **Technical Skills**

<b>Programming Languages:</b>	ASP.Net, C#, VB.Net, Java, Python, T-SQL
IDE:	Visual Studio Enterprise / TFS 2008/2012/2017; NetBeans; SQL Server Studio; VS Code, PyCharm
Web Technologies:	LINQ, JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, XML, J2EE, AJAX, Web Services
Framework:	MVC, Entity Framework, LINQ to SQL, Django
Development	Agile Development, UML Diagram
Methodologies:	
Exams:	MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional (2013); MS: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and
	CSS3 Specialist (2013); Level 2 ECDL certificate from BCS

#### Personal Skills

- Good communication skills and can work under pressure ensuring to deliver high quality work and paying attention to every detail.
- Ability to adapt in new environment, a good team player with ability to work independently in a fast-paced environment.
- Responsible to commitments, consistent and strong work ethic, utilise time management skills to demonstrate precision and punctuality.
- People focused, good at listening, valuing other people's idea and empathise others to encourage and appreciate their contributions

## **Employment History**

# Nov 2020- Present Tech Returners, Software Developer

London, Remote

During this programme I was able to upskill and refresh my software development skills and get better understanding of sponsor company's organisation structure, requirements and expectations for their various tech roles. Highlight has been to work with team in an agile environment and build a tech for good app. Working towards delivering a minimum viable product and present to stakeholders within the 8-week deadline.

# Jul 2019 – Present Global Escapes Ltd, Online Travel Consultant - Director (Part-time) Colchester, UK

During my career break I helped my husband to set up our online travel company and have been taking responsibility of following duties:

- Effectively planning, organising and managing the daily aspects of running company by looking after operational, financial
  and administrative duties.
- Promoting, marketing and managing holidays packages and travel arrangement for clients and providing them excellent customer services.
- Had a great opportunity to get involved in 3-months project contracted by Hays Travel and successfully worked as a COVID 19
   Vulnerable People Advisor. Efficiently provided service by making outbound calls to extremely medically vulnerable people,
   help them receive basic supplies of food, medicine and in some cases referring them to their local authority due to desperately
   needing help to in some case referring them to emergency services for immediate care.

Successfully created trust by engaging in meaningful interactions, actively listening and capturing the essential data to register them into government portal for any support.

#### Jun 2016 - Sep 2017 System Data Manager, Ayios Nikolaos Primary School

Cyprus

While accompanying my husband on his overseas tour, I worked in British MOD school providing direct support to our deployed service community. My responsibility was to ensure all families make the seamless transition at arriving and leaving school and providing them all the relevant information about the school.

#### Achievements:

- Effectively recorded, analysed, presented and managed pupil, staff and school's data on IntegrsG2 MIS system.
- Provided direct assistant to Head teacher for data and assessment. Ensured all the data in the school were accurate and up to date and provided relevant reports for students and parents and analysis for Senior Leaders.
- Managed the admissions process for prospective pupils effectively responding to all the enquiries and providing welcoming response to any enquiries concerning pupil admissions.

## Nov2012 - Oct 2015 Software Consultant/ Developer, Furlong Business Solutions

Andover, UK

I have had an opportunity to work in various roles as a software developer, consultant, tester and project manager during my time in the company. Gained experience working in an agile team, working closely with clients and delivering product to their expectation and providing technical assistance.

#### Achievements

- Gained experience on designing and developing desktop and web solutions for school-based data management system using MVC framework in ASP.Net programming language.
- Managed projects for data migration for local and international schools. Communicated well and dealt with the school data managers to understand their school's pupil and staff data structure and their old system. Achieved positive feedbacks from clients for providing them technical support for using our system and completing the project before the deadlines.
- Successfully completed numerous development assignments which required meeting with clients to gather specific requirements, designing, implementing, testing, bug fixing and providing technical assistance of the new product.

#### Jun 2010 -Jun 2011 Junior Software Developer, Staffordshire County Council

Stafford, UK

During my university placement, I worked in two diverse professional teams (MIS and GIS team) where I gained my first experience on developing real commercial projects for business clients. Contributed my work on their Time Recording system used for internal staff to record their working times while working with MIS team using Java. Involved on project of building School Patrol system for county with GIS team using .Net technology. I was also the part of BI reporting team assisting them with creating report using SAP.

#### Achievements

- Worked together person to person; team to team and service to service within the County Council.
- Developed theoretical skills by applying them in the real practical world.
- Gained knowledge of different hardware and software technologies used in council to achieve the objectives of business.
- Experience gained on SAP BI, web application development using .NET framework and desktop application using Java.

#### **Volunteering**

Contributing towards my society is always my priority and have always put myself forward for any volunteering opportunity. I utilise my technical knowledge and communication skills to pass on knowledge to help my community.

# Jan 2020 – Present Child Workforce Community Support Worker

Colchester, UK

• Provide support for young children by involving in running youth club for their personal and social development

# Sep2012 – Nov 2012 IT Buddies, Andover Neighbour Care Silver Surfer Internet Cafe Achievement

Andover, UK

# • Developed good communication skills with elderly customers and getting their positive feedbacks for my assistance they received during the course.

# Jan 2011 – Jun 2012 IT Buddies, Stafford Library

Stafford, UK

#### Achievement

- Opportunity to interact with different peoples and share basic knowledge of IT with them.
- Shared experiences and offered support to the basic learners creating a friendly environment.

## **Education**

# Sep-2008 – Jul 2012 BSc (Hons) Computing Science (2:1), Staffordshire University Dissertation Project A Prototype Enterprise Student Timetabling System

Stafford, UK

A prototype web-based application with Java EE, developed for students, enabling them to visualise and integrate their selected module's timetable into a clash-free master timetable. The application data synchronises with the live university timetable information system and notifies student of any changes in their subscribed master timetable.

#### **Achievement**

The Final year project won the first place in GradEx 2012 from the category of Computing and Information Systems. Gradex is an annual exhibition of final year projects of students in Faculty of Computing, Engineering and Technology.

#### Relevant Modules:

Algorithm and Data structure in C, Object oriented programming, System Modelling, Introduction to operating system, Further Object Oriented Programming, Further Programming C++, Database Systems, Current Programming in C#, Principle and Practises of Software Production, Graphical User Interface: Design and Implementation, Software Development for mobile computing, Algorithms, Design Patterns, Enterprise Application with Java Enterprise Edition, Advanced Programming language concepts, Project Management

**2006 – 2007** BEng (Hons) Computer Engineering (1<sup>st</sup> Year), Kantipur Engineering College
Computer Programming, I Practical (96), Physics Practical (92), Electric Circuits I Practical (90), Mathematics II (85), Communication (English) (85)

2004 – 2006 Science (Intermediate level equivalent to A levels), United Academy

Nepal

Mathematics (70), English (70), Chemistry (71), Physics (70)

1990 – 2003 School Leaving Certificate (SLC Equivalent to GCSE), Future Stars High

Nepal

School

References

References available upon request